But, humyan.
My myaster loves you.
So if you fall in love with my myaster, I think that might bottle me up.
Quit joking.
Even I'm not gonna fall for that one.
Plus, it's just terrible.
In this world, there are good lies and bad lies, and-
You really are stupid, humyan.
Do you think I'm clever enough to lie to you?
But, cat.
If that's not a lie...
Aren't you just mistaken?
There's no way she could be in love with me.
Why do you think that?
I wouldn't understand my myaster.
She's the only my myaster I have.
But-
But even though she loves you, you're going out with someone else.
And showing it off in front of her.
But Hanekawa isn't acting like that!
If anything, she wants me to be with Senjougahara! She's even given me advice-
That's exactly what has her so stressed, meow!
Do you think a girl like my myaster could work up the guts to ask you out?
She couldn't even let slip a single hint of it.
I don't know everything, I-
Wow, Hanekawa was-
How long?
How long has Hanekawa loved me?
Since spring break.
I guess my myaster thought the humyan/vyampire relationship thing was the purrfect thing
to break her free from the life she was sick of.
That's-
But she never would have expected a rival to appear, meow.
Meanwhile, the girl you're going out with moved in lightning-fast.
I never lie.
Wrong.
If this is true, you've told nothing but lies, Hanekawa Tsubasa!
A girl raised in a cold, unloving family.
During her spring break,
she has a shocking encounter with a supernyatural entity who happens to be a classmate.
It feels like fate. Her heart begins to stir.
Then, later, he saves her life-she's convinced that it's love.
Or something.
Whether she's right or wrong, she feels like she's had something purrecious snatched away from her.
Wait, cat.
There's something not quite right there.
Even if I'm the source of her stress like you're saying, that wouldn't be enough to release you.
There must be something else big that's stressing her out.
Wrong. It's all you.
But aren't you the embodiment of all the stress Hanekawa built up from her home life?
Just a couple months of love shouldn't-
"Just"?
And just what makes you think a few months of lovesickness
can't be worse than over a decade of family problems, meow?
What, haven't you ever really fallen for anyone?
Are you just dating that girl to shut her up?
You may as well dump her and get with my myaster, then.
I can't do that, cat.
Oh? Why not?
Don't you need to reward my myaster for everything she's done for you?
If I did that, Hanekawa would just be taking advantage of my debt to her.
I don't want to let her do that kind of thing.
No, that's not it. That's just a convenient excuse.
I can't deny my feelings for Senjougahara.
I figured you'd go for Hanekawa-san between the two of them.
Even with how she acts sometimes, I still love Senjougahara.
She's the first woman I've ever really loved.
Oh, is that so?
Plus, cat.
No matter the circumstances, it's Hanekawa's own weakness that brought you forth.
What you told me is something Hanekawa should have told me herself.
She's just forcing you to do the hard part.
There are plenty of people who've lived through the same problems Hanekawa is having
without relying on an aberration.
Her just relying on you is an insult to each one of them.
You've got some nerve to say that, meow.
Oh well, I guess you've earned the right.
After all, you're the guy so kindhearted he'd even sacrifice himself to save a mortally-wounded vyampire.
If you're kind to everyone, that means no humyan is special.
I understand that because my myaster was kind to everyone, too.
Oh well, there's no changing someone's feelings.
I learned that last time.
Learned it quite well, meow.
That's good.
I guess Hanekawa feels the same way, then?
Then I might have been a bit harsh scolding her like that.
What do you mean?
Well...
Vampires have a special charisma, right?
And because of it I've been popular with the girls since spring break.
Hanekawa told me that.
Hanekawa's always so serious. If she's so caught up in her feelings, she must  have been a victim of that.
Wait, why did you stop talking?
No, you're wrong.
A knockoff vyampire like you can't use his charismya at all.
But...
The power of charismya isn't a love potion like that, anyway.
It's the power to completely remove their will, purroducing nothing more than your very own marionette.
Marionette?
Not just infatuate them?
Well, just think, humyan.
Are any of the girls you know what you'd call "completely obedient"?
Is there anyone who'll do anything you say, with no questions asked?
Not a one.
Then...
Sorry, I'm just teasing.
That must have been-
There's no changing someone's feelings.
But that's not like my myaster at all.
I guess I gave it away by being too dumb to lie, meow.
Maybe that's another hard part she forced you to do.
I guess I should be proud that Hanekawa loves me.
Anyway, we need to find Shinobu.
Now that I think of it, no one I asked to help has gotten back to me yet.
I should probably tell Sengoku to call it off soon.
Hey, humyan.
There's one other way.
A way to confine me again without relying on a vyampire.
How?
Why don't you walk on over to that streetlight?
Like this?
A little bit further, meow.
You're right under it, so you don't have enough of a shadow there.
Shadow?
Cat, you-
I told you I didn't just come here to make friends.
I'm not pathetic enough yet to want to be friendly with a human.
What do you think this will accomplish?!
I told you I had another plan, meow.
I don't need to be here if the source of her stress-you-is gone.
That's-
Haven't you learned?!
When you attacked Hanekawa's parents during Golden Week...
Just doing that won't solve anything!
You didn't go away! You started attacking passersby!
Human stress isn't that simple!
I failed that time.
I didn't kill her parents, meow.
I've learned. I won't make the same mistake twice.
I will certainly kill you.
Kill...
But that's Hanekawa's inner thoughts.
Hanekawa's words.
I owe Hanekawa my life.
I'd do anything for her.
You should be happy.
You get to ride my myaster's naughty body straight to Heaven.
I'm dying for Hanekawa's sake.
No! I can't!
If Hanekawa kills me, Senjougahara will kill her for sure!
So I can't die!
That's the absolute worst way to handle it!
Let me go!
Just let me go!
Pleading for your life?
Very well. If you promise you'll be my myaster's lover, I'll let you go.
I told you, I can't!
You sure did.
Well, then.
Die.
Or maybe you could try calling for someone to help?
You've helped plenty of people, maybe one of them will return the favor.
One of them...
No one's going to save me.
No one? Why?
People just accept help selfishly, for their own sake.
You don't really think that, do you?
It's just something you say.
It's not how you feel, meow.
The question's how you really feel.
Maybe people do just accept help selfishly for their own sake-
but what does that have to do with the reasons their helper has?
How many people do you think want to help you?
Are you rejecting every one of them?
They'd be sad, wouldn't they.
Hanekawa and Senjougahara...
Kanbaru and Sengoku, too.
Even Hachikuji.
If I...
Save... me...
Save me...
Shinobu!
You don't have enough of a shadow there.
That's enough! Stop, Shinobu!
If you go any further, you'll kill Hanekawa too.
I don't want that.
Araragi-kun...
Don't say lonely things like, "I care more about my debt to you than our friendship."
Be nice, Araragi-kun.
Okay.
Come on, onii-chan, it's morning!
You need to get up!
Come on !
After that, Kanbaru, who had come to check up on us, helped me and Hanekawa home.
And that day, before school, I went to the ruined cram school.
To bring Shinobu, still hidden in my shadow, back to Oshino.
But...
You're late.
I had to stop for something.
How are you feeling?
Great.
Good morning.
I don't know yet how much Hanekawa remembers.
I need to ask her someday, but not now.
Hanekawa needs time to mend her heart, too.
Welcome back.
I'm back.
You get to plan our next date.
If you bring me somewhere weird, I'll flay you.
Sure.
I'm cool with that.
This time, I'll show you my treasure.
Someday even crabs need to start on a journey.
I had Kanbaru wait for us, and after school she,
Senjougahara, Hanekawa, and I went back to the ruined cram school.
One day, I'll leave this city.
Now I understand.
When I came here yesterday...
Oshino was outside getting ready to move on.
I won't just disappear without telling you.
I'm an adult, so I at least know to do that.
Why didn't I realize?
That line itself just had to have been a farewell.
He's the kind of person who never says goodbye.
That awkward man who hates farewells more than anything...
It shows just how deeply he cared about me.
When I went searching for for Shinobu, he let the meddlecat free on purpose, and left this place behind.
Because he believed I could handle Shinobu and Hanekawa myself.
Man, he really was.
Yeah, he was.
Definitely.
He sure was.
A nice guy.
I may meet more aberrations in the future.
But that's okay.
Now I know.
There's dark places in this world, and things that live in them.
Even within my own shadow.
The culture festival finally starts tomorrow.
Our class project is-
a haunted house.